RICHARD SEWARD

Loveland, CO 80537 | (970) 430-8559 | raseward14@gmail.com

Links

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-seward-7b9336102/
- https://github.com/raseward14
- https://raseward14.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

Professional Summary

Motivated full stack developer with a passion for lifelong learning! Specialize in utilizing multiple programming languages & tools to create interactive online platforms that draw users in with intuitive UI's. Recently received a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Denver. Well versed in fast paced work environments susceptible to ever changing client requests and processes.

Technical Skills

HTML5 | Node.js | Express | CSS3 | JavaScript | JQuery | React.js | React | JSX | MongoDB | MySQL |
Mongoose | Handlebars | Bootstrap | Materialize | APIs | Heroku | Terminal | AJAX | Restful API | ES6 |
React Hooks | JSON | Sequelize | Responsive Design | GIT | GitHub | Gitub | Bulma

- Microsoft: Outlook | Teams | Apps
- Google: Drive | Docs | Sheets | File Sharing
- Colorado Notary Public

Relevant Experience | Projects

My Cheap Book Finder | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link:

https://raseward14.github.io/My_Cheap_Book_Finder/ | Github Link:

https://github.com/raseward14/My_Cheap_Book_Finder

My Cheap Book Finder gives the user a list of 5 suggested books based on their search. Click your book to see several book listings, each with eBay buy links.

- Role: Used JavaScript to fetch 3rd party API's Google books and eBay marketplace. Managed the teams GitHub project, creating, reviewing, and approving pull requests. Finalized HTML page by manipulating DOM using JavaScript functionality.
- Utilized: HTML5, CSS3, JSON GET requests, Server-side API's; eBay marketplace, Google books, JavaScript

Weather Dashboard | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: https://raseward14.github.io/Weather-

<u>Dashboard</u> | **Github Link:** https://github.com/raseward14/Weather-Dashboard

Search for a city to see today's forecast, as well as the 5-day extended forecast with corresponding icons. User searches are saved as list items to revisit later.

- Role: Created HTML page styled with CSS to add Server-Side API data with bootstrap framework. Fetched data from OpenWeather to display current, and extended forecast data. Dynamically updated HTML by manipulating DOM with vanilla JavaScript to list searched cities below input field. Utilized local storage to display recently searched cities on page load.
- Utilized: HTML5, CSS3, JSON GET requests, Server-side API's; OpenWeather, JavaScript, JQuery

Work Day Scheduler | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: https://raseward14.github.io/Work-Day-Scheduler | Github Link: https://github.com/raseward14/Work-Day-Scheduler

Plan your day by saving events in standard business hour blocks. Using Moment.js, the current hour is always red, future is green, and past is grey.

- Role: Designed front end display with HTML5 and styled CSS3. Utilized JQuery to implement Moment.js functionality, including a header that displays current date, background colors for each time block that correlated to past, present, and future CSS3 classes. Local Storage is utilized to save events, and data attributes are assigned dynamically by manipulating the DOM with JavaScript.
- Utilized: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, moment.js library

Web API Quiz | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: https://raseward14.github.io/Web-API-Quiz/ | Github Link: https://github.com/raseward14/Web-API-Quiz

How well do you know web development? Take the quiz and find out. But be careful, incorrect answers deduct time. Save your score on the high scores page.

- **Role:** Dynamically updated HTML styled with CSS3 by manipulating DOM with vanilla javascript. Bootstrap elements are heavily integrated to give the final application a clean polished look. Local storage is utilized to save high scores.
- Utilized: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Vanilla JavaScript, Media Queries, Responsive Design

Work History

Staffing Recruiter 08/2019 to Current

Elwood Staffing – Longmont, CO

- Interviewed (up to 40 daily), 200+ daily emails, recruit, onboard, offboard, orientation, counsel, resume building, job fairs,
- Associate i9's ID verification, drug screens, background checks, and workers comp, HFWA 25+ client onboarding SOP's, P&L review, payroll
- Consistently exceeded year to date net income
- 5-time Superior Customer Service award recipient.

International English Teacher

10/2016 to 03/2019

IQ International School – Siem Reap, Siem Reap, Cambodia

- Successfully developed clear, concise lessons, classroom management, 'Back Pocket Activities', track progress, advanced MS Excel Pivot Table, Mc at school events, filmed inspiring school videos
- Developed running club, football club, cursive writing, reading comprehension, Sport & Fitness courses, library read at home program
- Built English mathematics curriculum grades 4 9

Project Management Intern

06/2016 to 09/2016

EdVenture International – Bangkok, Bangkok, Thailand

- Humanitarian educational development Southeast Asia
- Coordinated participant travel logistics, project contribution
- Collected "best" photos, participant reflections, leadership workshops
- Stationed in Thailand at Bantaklang elephant village, Chiang Mai, Baan Don Chai Girls School, Bangkok, and in Cambodia at Sopheak's Friendship School and Phum Oh in Siem Reap city.

Denver Math Fellow 06/2015 to 05/2016

AmeriCorps – Denver, CO

- Classroom management, lesson planning, data tracking & entry
- Successfully increased 35% of students MAP test scores by 1 or more math grade levels, WIDA, PARCC, MAP, ANET test proctor, analysis
- No nonsense nurturer & Professional Dev. Courses
- Founded Middle School XC, Frisbee Club, Hip Hop Dance team

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Expected in 05/2021

University of Denver - Denver, CO

• Continuing education in Full Stack Development

BBA: Management & Economics

12/2014

Colorado Mesa University - Grand Junction, CO

- Graduated cum laude, 3.67 GPA, Deans List Fall 2010-Fall 2014
- Men's Varsity XC/T&F Team: 4 yr.'s, Team Captain 2014
- Phi Beta Lambda: 4 yr.'s Director of Membership 2012